Mahreen Ayaz . Jarvis Consulting

I am a skilled Data Analyst and Business System Analyst having just completed University of Toronto's Data Analytics program. With experience in Waterfall, Agile, and Scrum, I excel in Python, SQL, Excel, VBA, SAP, and project management tools. In my role at Enzen Global, UK, I coordinated scheduling, tracked tasks on JIRA, and contributed to business process modelling. My passion lies in applying analytical and technical skills to Data Analytics or Business System Analysis roles. My strong communication, collaboration, and project management skills make me an ideal candidate for contributing to project success and process excellence.

Skills

Proficient: RDBMS/SQL, Agile/Scrum, Git, Excel, Project/Stakeholder Management

Competent: Python, Linux/Bash, Tableau, Agile and Scrum, Business Process Management

Familiar: SAP, System Analysis, VBA, JIRA, ServiceNow

Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis data eng MahreenAyaz

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: The application has been developed to collect resource usage data from the Virtual Machine and insert it into Postgres tables. This has been achieved by implementing two bash scripts. The first host_info.sh collects the system hardware specs and stores them in the host_info table. The second script, host_usage.sh, collects the system usage parameters and stores them in the host_usage table. The has been scheduled using crontab to collect the data every minute. The Postgres itself is installed in a docker container. Furthermore, the creation/start/stop functionality of the docker container has also been implemented through psql_docker.sh. Also, a ddl.sql was developed to deploy the tables. The application has been deployed using Git version control.

BSA Fundamentals Project [GitHub]: Produced a comprehensive BRD (Business Requirement Document) for Linux cluster Monitoring application. Also, involved in the elicitation and development of a user-centric stock trading application, aligning with business objectives outlined in the SRD. Utilized preferred technology stack and implemented security measures, ensuring high availability and real-time data updates.

Highlighted Projects

Improvement of field operations reporting at Enzen Global: Analyzed and improved the reporting process for field operations at Enzen Global. The field workers submitted their progress status at the end of their workday. This was used to plan the activities for the next days and send reports to stakeholders. I worked to streamline these processes and ensure there were no gaps in the process. The reporting was also overhauled to make it more meaningful.

Professional Experiences

Business System Analyst, Jarvis (2023-present): Working as a BSA at Jarvis and involved in internal projects and training. I have successfully delivered Python, Bash and SQL-related projects.

Business System Analyst, Enzen Global (2014-2017): Worked as a BSA at Enzen Global where I was responsible for day-to-day business operations and reporting. I was responsible for managing and scheduling a team of field workers and then reporting on their progress to the stakeholders. These included not only internal executives but also customers. I was also involved in project management, process management and continuous improvement tasks. I regularly used tools like SQL, SAP, ServiceNow and Excel to complete my tasks.

Education

University of Toronto (2023), Diploma in Data Analytics, School of Continuing Studies

University of Houston Clearlake (2012-2014), MS Environmental Sciences, Environmental Sciences

Miscellaneous

• Hiking: I absolutely love hiking and I usually go on the weekends with my kids. It's not just a great way to stay physically active, but it also teaches me perseverance and the importance of reaching new heights.

- Traveling: Traveling is one of my great passions. Experiencing different cultures has not only broadened my perspective but has also made me more adaptable and open-minded. Among the European countries that I have visited, Italy was my favorite.
- Home Decor: I have a keen interest in home decor. It might seem like an unusual hobby, but I find joy in creating a comfortable and aesthetically pleasing living space. It's about creating an environment that's not only functional but also enjoyable.